<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tumbling Owl</title>
    <description>cdr255&#39;s personal blog</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Jekyll and Hyde: Moving from Blogger to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been blogging and maintaining personal websites for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My most recent foray has been, largely, a success: I have had 8
different blogs hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/&quot; title=&quot;Google&#39;s Blogging Service.&quot;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt; over the last two
years. However, the downsides to this are twofold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, and foremost: I have &lt;strong&gt;Eight&lt;/strong&gt; blogs. Content on all of them
has been a trickle, mostly because I tend to focus on updating one or
two of them instead of each one in succession. This balkanization of
my blogging has been a big detrement to me for a while, so I recently
decided that it might be smart to go down to one blog only… at least
for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second… I write all of my posts using the markup language
&lt;a href=&quot;kramdown.gettalong.org/&quot; title=&quot;My personal markup language of choice.&quot;&gt;kramdown&lt;/a&gt; (which is really a dialect of
[markdown][md]). Blogger supports posts written in only two formats:
HTML, and their own “Rich Text Editor.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means for me is that I have to compile my posts on my own
computer before uploading them to the web. So, why put up with some of
the annoyances of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/&quot; title=&quot;Google&#39;s Blogging Service.&quot;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt; if I am doing static site
generation anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, I chose to move to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;This whole site is rendered with Jekyll.&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It was quite a process,
but that is a different post. I am very happy with it so far, and will
update more on it as I begin to migrate everything over to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope it all goes smoothly from here on out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christopher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 08:50:55 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/jekyll/update/2014/05/23/Jekyll-and-Hyde/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jekyll/update/2014/05/23/Jekyll-and-Hyde/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the &lt;code&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; switch) to see your changes!
To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 06:53:26 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/jekyll/update/2014/05/23/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/jekyll/update/2014/05/23/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NaruShippuUlti3FB Beat the Main story of Ultimate Ninja Storm 3!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1149 Words. Estimated Reading Time: 5 Minutes, 45 Seconds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Naruto Shippuden Ultimate Ninja Storm 3 Full Burst is a
  fighting game, and may just be my favorite fighting game in the last
  5 years..&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/9A8UdCx.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/9A8UdCx.png&quot; alt=&quot;NSUNS3FB Title Screen&quot; title=&quot;A lot of
people will not even consider this game because it has ties to the
Naruto Franchise. It&#39;s a shame, because of how well done and tightly
made this game is. If You are on the fence about playing this game
just because it has the Naruto name all over it, I implore You to just
give it a shot. You will not be
disappointed.&quot; class=&quot;displayleft&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve just recently completed my first run through of the main story of
this game, &lt;em&gt;Naruto Shippuden Ultimate Ninja Storm 3 Full Burst&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long title, I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I have to say that this game is probably my favorite fighting
game of the last 5 years. It is innovative in a few crucial ways while
not sacrificing accessibility or gameplay, and it does it all in a
very tight and engaging package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has a large amount of characters which all play differently, and
the standard game is played with one main and two supporting
characters, allowing for a very large amount of versus
matchups. Characters has references to the story worked into the
gameplay itself, and not just into the story of the game… As in, a
character who is slow plays slow, a character who focuses on items or
melee is designed to be focused on that, and every character has a
mode where they will break away from the way most other characters
play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Lbsv6e6.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Lbsv6e6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Example of Combat Screen&quot; title=&quot;It is kinda hard to get a good screenshot of the combat of this game
while You are fighting, especially since the game is played with a
controller. I&#39;ll be talking about the game again on here, and by then
I will hopefully have a better screenshot to use... I&#39;ll have some
friends over to play while I work the keyboard. Should be good.&quot; class=&quot;displayright&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To digress for a second: Yes, it is a Naruto product. And no, &lt;em&gt;even if
You are not a fan of the series&lt;/em&gt;, it does not suck. No familiarity
with the story is needed to enjoy the game, as any needed backstory is
well represented within it. You will not be at a true disadvantage
versus someone really interested in the series, provided You play the
game enough to learn the rules and characters &lt;em&gt;as You would have to do
with any other fighting game&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fights are done in an arena style battlefield with a dynamic
camera. For 1 vs 1 battles (all versus matches and most story matches)
the camera works absolutely wonderfully. There are a few points in the
story when You fight “6 vs 2” battles (which is in quotes because it
is really 6 vs 1 + 1 support) or have beat’em up style dungeons to
walk through. The camera isn’t &lt;em&gt;horrible&lt;/em&gt; then, but You may have to
use that right stick more often in these few segments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ItdCrBf.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ItdCrBf.png&quot; alt=&quot;Combat Still 2&quot; title=&quot;An interesting facet of the battle system in this game, the cut scene
attacks [Jutsus, Throws, and Team Attacks] break up the monotony on
screen. They are easily blockable, easily dodgeable, take a lot of
energy and in no way are overpowered, which makes the fact that they
&amp;quot;pause the game&amp;quot; for a few seconds much more forgivable. Also, it is
really nice to see big moves from the show used in the game in a fair
way. Maybe that is a personal point, but I AM the author here.&quot; class=&quot;displayleft&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the combat itself: Instead of a combo-based move list like many
games in the fighting genre, this game created a large amount of
different kinds of commands. This makes for less memorization of combos
(Ex. &lt;em&gt;Quarter Circle Forward, A, Down, Back, B&lt;/em&gt;) and more a
memorization of abilities (Ex. &lt;em&gt;The Second Mizukage has many good
projectile attacks, and if he is cornered should back away as soon as
possible&lt;/em&gt;). However, this is different from most fighting games, so I
will clarify a few things about the control: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can still do a minimum of three melee combo strings per character,
but You can also: “throw” enemies, which really results in a move
which throws the enemy away from You; use two different kinds of
special move (Jutsu) which, provided they hit the enemy, play out in a
cutscene; throw projectiles which will stop an enemy for a split
second, breaking their commands or wasting their abilities; call upon
support from one of two team mates, who will either continue a combo
for You, hit an enemy with a special move, or (provided You have
filled a certain bar) gang up on Your enemy in a high-damage cutscene
where You all three juggle Your opponent, finishing with Your
strongest single move; Use three dimensional movement to dance around
the battlefield, able to dodge most attacks but unable to really do
damage, as a way to change the distance between You and Your opponent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/RijifLt.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/RijifLt.png&quot; alt=&quot;Legend vs Hero Concept&quot; title=&quot;One of the coolest aspects of this specific entry in this series is
this, the system of Legend vs. Hero that it has. Basically, You can
choose at certain points to take one of two choices [called an
Ultimate Decision in game] which will change the conditions
[and cutscenes] for the coming battle. There are also two different
sets of items in the game, which You can only use to support one of
the two choices. Pretty deep for a fighting game, and allows for a lot of
interesting choices.&quot; class=&quot;displayright&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are more commands, but this is already really long, so I’ll move
on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is decent, though if You &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; cannot stand Naruto, then
every story cutscene is skippable, and will not cause the game to be
unplayable. It is worked into the game very well, and I can easily
say I would play through it again: They have a few very interestingly
different situations which occurred in the story, and they were both
challenging and fun. Then, there is the Legend vs Hero system,
described in this image. Just, a lot of depth for a fighting game,
story wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the main game is complete, You are given free reign to walk
around and engage people in the beautifully rendered 3D world. This is
where I currently am, and so I’d better get to completing it, so I can
talk about it too. I hope it doesn’t take me too too long!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christopher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 14:52:55 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/video_games/anime/preblog/2014/03/31/Naruto-Shippuden-Ultimate-Ninja-Storm-3-Full-Burst/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/video_games/anime/preblog/2014/03/31/Naruto-Shippuden-Ultimate-Ninja-Storm-3-Full-Burst/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
