<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tumbling Owl</title>
    <description>The personal web log of Christopher Rodriguez.</description>
    <link>http://www.tumblingowl.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.tumblingowl.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am testing out jekyll as a new way to serve my blogs to the
net. Hopefully I will be able to make it work enough to the point
where I can upload this as my blog soon, at http://www.tumblingowl.com
or something similar.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 14:33:33 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.tumblingowl.com/test/meta/short/2014/08/14/hello-world/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tumblingowl.com/test/meta/short/2014/08/14/hello-world/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the &lt;code&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; switch) to see your changes!
To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 14:21:33 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.tumblingowl.com/jekyll/update/2014/08/14/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tumblingowl.com/jekyll/update/2014/08/14/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resurgence of My Interest in (Game and Software) Development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Word Count: ~346, Estimated Reading Time: About 1 Minutes, 44 Seconds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 10 (or, wow, 13 now… I am getting &lt;em&gt;old&lt;/em&gt;) years ago, I stumbled
upon &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catb.org/esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html#skills1&quot;&gt;ESR’s guide&lt;/a&gt; on learning to “Become a Hacker.” That link
goes to the relevant section for this post, but if You are interested
in becoming active with Your computer I recommend reading the entire
thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a good thing I did. It set me on the right path, though I have
chosen a very interesting way to follow it so far… I started with
&lt;strong&gt;C++&lt;/strong&gt; and, though I have learned a great many concepts I would not
have learned otherwise, it could easily be argued that I could have
learned so much more had I started with a language such as
&lt;a href=&quot;http://learnpythonthehardway.org/book/&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, ESR himself says so, in that very article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my move mostly settled, I am able to (once again) renew my
personal efforts in learning to design and implement programs. This
article is meant to outline the various things I want to do; This is a
sort of roadmap for my progress in this area. Of course, my own
mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/&quot;&gt;Java&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://learn.perl.org/&quot;&gt;Perl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubymonk.com/&quot;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clisp.org/&quot;&gt;Lisp&lt;/a&gt; better.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I have focussed far too much on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cplusplus.com/doc/tutorial/&quot;&gt;C++&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://learnpythonthehardway.org/book/&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.htmldog.com/guides/html/&quot;&gt;HTML/CSS&lt;/a&gt; these past few years (but mostly C++) and so, first on
my list is to shore up my weaknesses in other commonly used
languages.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;strong&gt;constructing algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;designing
programs&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;implementing concepts&lt;/strong&gt; from a &lt;em&gt;language
agnostic&lt;/em&gt; standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Syntax is one thing, but the &lt;strong&gt;ideas&lt;/strong&gt; behind a lot of programs
(and translating those ideas &lt;em&gt;into&lt;/em&gt; the syntax) is another, and a
much more important one.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complete&lt;/strong&gt; projects.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;No matter how small, insignigicant, or seemingly arbitrary, it is
&lt;em&gt;vital&lt;/em&gt; to both my motivation and my progress to actually finish
projects, instead of abandoning them halfway through.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be posting on here a lot about the things I learn, in the hopes
that doing so will further cement the information in my mind. Other
than that, I should get coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christopher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 09:33:16 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.tumblingowl.com/programming/game_design/2014/06/04/Resurgence-of-interest-in-dev/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tumblingowl.com/programming/game_design/2014/06/04/Resurgence-of-interest-in-dev/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pokemon Blue Chesslocke #000 - Tortellini, Jalapeno, and Cinnamon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Word Count: ~305, Estimated Reading Time: About 1 Minutes, 31 Seconds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I have decided to do a [Chesslocke][chesslocke] of Pokemon Blue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, this limits my run through of the game to catching only 16
pokemon: 1 King (starter), 1 Queen, 2 Bishops, 2 Rooks, 2 Knights, and
8 Pawns. The Rules for this Nuzlocke derivative would come into effect
after &lt;strong&gt;I receive my 5 free Pokeballs from Professor Oak&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been dubbed Jalaini (pronounced like ha-la-i-ni) by two of my
friends, who suggested the words “Jalapeno” and “Tortillini” for
character names. This makes my rival’s name “Torpeno”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My trainer ID is &lt;strong&gt;47794&lt;/strong&gt;, which means (according to the optional rule I am
using) my starter is the Fire type, Charmander. As a theme, all of my
pokemon will be named after spices. I named my charmander after one of
my favorites: “Cinnamon”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cinnamon&lt;/strong&gt; defeated Torpeno’s Squirtle fairly handily, though the
rules of the Challenge were not yet in effect. We easily made it to
&lt;em&gt;Viridian City&lt;/em&gt; and back, to deliver Oak’s Parcel to him. In exchange,
we recieved the high tech encyclopedia, &lt;strong&gt;Pokedex&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excited and brave, we never ran from any pokemon who chose to
challenge us during this time. On our way to scope out our goal,
&lt;em&gt;Victory Road&lt;/em&gt;, we once again ran into our rival. However, Torpeno had
caught himself a Pidgey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the rules of the challenge were still not quite in effect. We
had quite a difficult time beating this doubly strong combo, thought
we did eventually come out on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, being the responsible kid I am, I ran back to tell on him to his
grandfather, Professor Oak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He gave me 5 pokeballs for my troubles, and the full rules of the
challenge came into effect. Cinnamon, now level 11, and I set out that
very minute, ready for whatever kind of adventure would unfold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[chesslocke]: http://nuzlocke.wikia.com/wiki/Chesslocke “”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 13:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.tumblingowl.com/video_games/2014/05/28/Blue-Chesslocke-000-Introduction/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tumblingowl.com/video_games/2014/05/28/Blue-Chesslocke-000-Introduction/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Monday Multiplayer #0001 - Armagetron Advanced</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Word Count: ~267, Estimated Reading Time: About 1 Minute, 20 Seconds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/oPNXpRn.png&quot; alt=&quot;Start Screen&quot; title=&quot;Armagetron Advanced starts up and allows You to set
up a game in less than a minute. Very fast and easy
to learn.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Armagetron Advanced][armagetronad] is a modern tron-like game which
supports up to 16 simultaneous players. It supports many people
playing on one system, and many systems playing on one LAN. It runs on
&lt;strong&gt;GNU/Linux&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;MS Windows&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Mac OSX&lt;/strong&gt;, If You happen to use
&lt;strong&gt;0install&lt;/strong&gt;, it is also in that repository. It is Free, Libre, Open
Source software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basics of the game are simple: You ride around in a square room on
a tron bike, attempting to last longer than all of the other
players. Behind Your bike is a light trail, which is solid for all
intents and purposes. The default mode makes this light trail
permanent and of infinite length, making the game harder the longer it
goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/r4q8IxL.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot During Gameplay&quot; title=&quot;During gameplay, the camera will follow You
smartly. There are only three movement controls:
left, right, and brake. There is a chat function,
but it is only really useful after You have
already died.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can change most of the settings, if You are the one who is running
the server: You can have the room be huge or tiny, the bikes be fast
or slow, light trails decay or be permanent, bots join or leave, teams
set up or broken, and even control the music which plays in the
background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It falls flat for me in that, other than the built in scoring system,
there is very little in the terms of development over the course of a
night. It is very close to the original in terms of abstract
mechanics, and that leaves me wanting something more complex. But for
a social event, or a quick break from more complex games, I go to this
one first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/hoMyvTv.png&quot; alt=&quot;Watching the Chaos&quot; title=&quot;With a large amount of players or bots, the
game can get quite hectic. The basic game is 10
rounds, and rarely takes more than 10 minutes,
especially with a decent number of people. Try
this game out today!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is an easy, lightweight game to set up, and is perfect for an
impromtu LAN Party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christopher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 08:37:34 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.tumblingowl.com/video_games/2014/05/26/Armagetron-AD/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tumblingowl.com/video_games/2014/05/26/Armagetron-AD/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sunday Tabletop #0001 - Shadowrun Character Creation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Word Count: ~718, Estimated Reading Time: About 3 Minutes, 36 Seconds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Sunday Gaming Group recently switched from Pathfinder over to
Shadowrun (5th Edition).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had one character creation day, and it went well, though we are
having a second one today because of some absentees and for others to
finish up. It’s also the time of year when getting everyone in the
same room seems to become difficult, so there is that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My character is nearly finished, I just have to write out his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdr255.com/content/games/Character-Detail-Sheet.doc&quot;&gt;Character Detail Sheet&lt;/a&gt; so that he is fully fleshed out. I’ve just now added a page for him on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdr255.com&quot;&gt;my website&lt;/a&gt; if You would like to check his sheet out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I thought that I would talk a bit (briefly, don’t worry) about
character creation in Shadowrun. It comes down to about 7 or 8 steps,
and though I lost access to my scratch file for Keith over there, I
wanted to at least delineate those steps here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;You have to have a character concept (ie at least a bit of
fluff) before You can make a character.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Priorities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This appears to be the most difficult for new players to wrap their
heads around, so I will take a few sentences to explain it a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Basically, there are 5 rankings: A, B, C, D, and E. A is the ‘best’
and E is the ‘worst.’ Calling them rankings instead of priorities
helped me, as I grew up on jrpgs and other video games where You
can have a character with a high ranking/level in one thing and a
low ranking/level in another.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;You also have 5 parts to Your character: Metatype, Attributes,
Skills, Resources, and Magic/Resonance. Now, the important part:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You need to assign each of those 5 parts a ranking, and can only
use each ranking once.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Then, You use the table in the book to note what that gets Your
character. That is pretty much it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attributes and Special Attributes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Depends on two rankings: Your Metatype and Your Attributes.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;You spend Your Attribute points on the following attributes: &lt;strong&gt;BOD,
AGI, REA, STR, WIL, LOG, INT,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;CHA.&lt;/strong&gt; Your special attribute
points, on the other hand, go to: &lt;strong&gt;EDG, MAG,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;RES&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Spend all of them; they cannot be saved.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Qualities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;If You have played Dnd or Pathfinder, these are like Feats and Flaws.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;You start with 25 Karma. You can spend exactly 25 Karma on positive
qualities. You can also gain up to 25 Karma by taking negative
qualities. You can &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; spend more than 25 Karma on positive
qualities. You also can &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; gain more than 25 Karma by taking
negative qualities.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Do not feel like You have to use all of Your Karma, It is actually
useful in step 6.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills, Group Skills, and Knowledge Skills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This was the part which annoyed me the most. You have the two
values from Your priority chosed for skill: Your normal skill
points / Your group skill points. However, there is a third type of
skill point which is hidden in the skill section of the text (page
89, if You need a reference.)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Every character gains &lt;strong&gt;Knowledge Skill Points&lt;/strong&gt; equal to (INT +
LOG) x 2. This should really be stated better in the text, as our
entire group nearly missed it. These points can only be spent on
Knowledge Skills.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Also, You get one language at the rank of ‘N’ for free.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is shopping. Spend money, get things. Only note I have is You
need to spend to get under 5000 nuyen, or lose that money for no
reason.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is the most fluid section. I would recommend talking to Your
DM about it, or if You are the DM, reading the section in
full. Basically, You can use Karma for a bunch of things,
including: Familiars, Contacts, Skills, Magic, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finishing Up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;There are some final calculations to make, as well as Your
character details. Basic TTRPG stuff here. Hard work is done
already.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there You have it. A finished shadowrun character in 7 or 8
steps. Depending on how things go today, I may talk more about it in
the future as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christopher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 07:35:58 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.tumblingowl.com/tabletop_games/2014/05/25/Shadowrun-5th/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tumblingowl.com/tabletop_games/2014/05/25/Shadowrun-5th/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Saturday Renaissance #0001 - Bransle Pinagay</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/lw7zJru.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bransle Pinagay in Modern Notation&quot; title=&quot;Bransle Pinagay in Modern Notation. The first court dance I learned.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To hear what this sounds like, I have a MIDI file available &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/midi/bransle-pinagay.midi&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Kf4VNMX.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bransle Pinagay in Mensural Notation&quot; title=&quot;Bransle Pinagay in Mensural Notation. The first court dance I learned.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To perform this dance, You need a line or a circle of dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Section A:  1  - 4    Double left,
            5         Kick left.
            6  - 9    Double left,
            10 - 12   Kick left, right, left.
            
Section B:  13 - 16   Double left,
            17 - 20   Double right.
            21 - 24   Double left,
            25 - 28   Double right.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the original pages from my 1596 version of &lt;strong&gt;Orchesographie&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/nzzBJVR.png&quot; alt=&quot;Orchesographie Page 151&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/dUluaLH.png&quot; alt=&quot;Orchesographie Page 152&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 10:09:07 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.tumblingowl.com/music/2014/05/24/Bransle-Pinagay/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tumblingowl.com/music/2014/05/24/Bransle-Pinagay/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jekyll and Hyde: Moving from Blogger to Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been blogging and maintaining personal websites for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My most recent foray has been, largely, a success: I have had 8
different blogs hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/&quot; title=&quot;Google&#39;s Blogging Service.&quot;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt; over the last two
years. However, the downsides to this are twofold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, and foremost: I have &lt;strong&gt;Eight&lt;/strong&gt; blogs. Content on all of them
has been a trickle, mostly because I tend to focus on updating one or
two of them instead of each one in succession. This balkanization of
my blogging has been a big detrement to me for a while, so I recently
decided that it might be smart to go down to one blog only… at least
for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second… I write all of my posts using the markup language
&lt;a href=&quot;kramdown.gettalong.org/&quot; title=&quot;My personal markup language of choice.&quot;&gt;kramdown&lt;/a&gt; (which is really a dialect of
[markdown][md]). Blogger supports posts written in only two formats:
HTML, and their own “Rich Text Editor.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means for me is that I have to compile my posts on my own
computer before uploading them to the web. So, why put up with some of
the annoyances of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/&quot; title=&quot;Google&#39;s Blogging Service.&quot;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt; if I am doing static site
generation anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, I chose to move to &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;This whole site is rendered with Jekyll.&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It was quite a process,
but that is a different post. I am very happy with it so far, and will
update more on it as I begin to migrate everything over to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope it all goes smoothly from here on out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christopher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 08:50:55 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.tumblingowl.com/jekyll/update/2014/05/23/Jekyll-and-Hyde/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tumblingowl.com/jekyll/update/2014/05/23/Jekyll-and-Hyde/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the &lt;code&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; switch) to see your changes!
To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;Tom&#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &#39;Hi, Tom&#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2014 06:53:26 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.tumblingowl.com/jekyll/update/2014/05/23/welcome-to-jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tumblingowl.com/jekyll/update/2014/05/23/welcome-to-jekyll/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Iced Tea</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Word Count: ~482, Estimated Reading Time: About 2 Minutes, 25 Seconds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tl;dr:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A quick and easy sugar drink with a nice amount of
  caffeine. Perfect for getting me through the day, even if the day is
  opposed to the idea.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/FxcfTen.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/FxcfTen.png&quot; alt=&quot;A Pitcher of Iced Tea&quot; title=&quot;I store the finished product described here in a
cheap plastic pitcher I picked up one day when it
was marked down to a dollar, and put the pitcher
in the fridge. Though it rarely lasts longer than
a day- especially if I am not the only one
drinking it- It will keep a good long while in the
fridge, maybe 2 weeks or so before becoming
questionable.&quot; class=&quot;displayleft&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Ingredient&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Amount&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Price (Bulk)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Price (Used)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Option&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Tea Bags&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5 Units&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;100 Units / $5.00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.25&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;All&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sugar&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1/2 Cup&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10 lbs / $4.98&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.11&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;All&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Tap Water&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2 Qt&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 kGal / $5.05&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.26&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;All&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Lemon&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 Unit&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 Unit / $0.40&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.40&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;A       :&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Lemon Juice&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3 Tbsp&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;32 fl oz / $1.29&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.06&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;B       :&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lemons are better for You, but Lemon Juice is much cheaper.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start, bring 1.5 Qts of tap water to a boil. While waiting, add 1
Pt of cold water to a cup or bowl. Add Lemon Juice to cold water, and
Tea Bags to a 2 Qt glass or earthenware bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once boiling, add Tap Water to Tea Bags. Brew for 7 minutes (Iced tea
should be brewed about 180% normal time, to give it strong
flavor). Remove the Tea Bags, add Sugar, and stir until dissolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add Lemon Water to the Sugared Tea. Bring to a bit over room
temperature, store in a pitcher in the freezer for about an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;comparison&quot;&gt;Comparison&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Common Option&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Cost per Unit (1/2 Gal)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Diff per Unit (Opt A)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Diff per Unit (Opt B)&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Arizona&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1.49&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+$0.40&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+$0.74&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Wawa&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1.79&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+$0.70&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;+$1.04&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;my-thoughts&quot;&gt;My Thoughts&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a simple formula for a very reliable beverage. You can
customize this many ways to suit a variety of tastes or needs, and can
easily emulate most flavors out on the market for much less than they
charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference is not so much that buying it to drink while You are
out is stupid, but if You can, it is much better to make it home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do it Yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christopher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;cost-table-details-in-source&quot;&gt;Cost Table (Details in Source)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Option Group&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Cost per Unit (w/ Energy)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Cost per Unit (w/o Energy&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Option A&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1.09&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$1.02&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Option B&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.75&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;$0.68&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;nutrition-table-details-in-source&quot;&gt;Nutrition Table (Details in Source)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Calories per Unit&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Calories per Serving&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Carbs (g/kCal/%)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Protein (g/kCal/%)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Fats (g/kCal/%)&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;406 kCal (406.51)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;51 kCal (51.81)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;106.10g / 403.79kCal / 99.33%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.64g / 1.7kCal / 0.41%&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0.17g / 1.7kCal / 0.25%&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;!-- 5 tea bags @ 100 / $5.00 = 0.25
1/2 C sugar @ 10lbs (24 C) / $4.98 = 0.11
2 Qt Water @ 1000 Gal / $5.05 = 0.26
1 Lemon @ 1 Units / $0.40 = 0.40

Price roughly $1.02, without energy costs.

!!! With Lemon Juice @ 1 qt / $1.29 and 3 tbsp = 1 Lemon,
lemon cost becomes $0.06, making pre energy costs flatten
to 0.68. !!!


Energy costs estimate: 0.18 / kWh (Average from sample bills on
internet, incl. supply and delivery)

1.5kW kettle * 0.25 hours = 0.375 kWh

0.375 kWh * $0.18 = 0.0675

Adding energy costs, about $0.93 a half gallon.

Assuming daily use, per quarter this adds roughly $6.08 to the
electric bill of a household.



Compare to price of Arizona or Wawa Tea:

Arizona: 2.78/gallon + (2.78 * 0.07) or (0.1946) or 0.20 tax =

         $2.98/gallon, $1.49 half gallon, or +$0.40 / half gallon.

Assuming daily consumption, this would be a difference of $50.40 per
quarter.

Wawa: usually on sale for 3 half gal/$5.00, meaning 1 = 1.6667,
or 1 half gal @ $1.67. Adding tax, this comes to

         $1.79 half gallon, or +0.70 / half gallon.

Assuming daily consumption, this would be a difference of $77 per
quarter.

Nutrition Facts:

Calories per half gallon: 17 + 387 + 2 = 406 kCal

Calories from Carbs: 2 + 387 + 14.79 = 403.79 kCal

Grams from Carbs: 0.71 + 99.98 + 5.41 = 106.10g

Calories from Fats: 1.02 = 1.02 kCal

Grams from Fats: 0 + 0 + 0.17 = 0.17g

Calories from Proteins: 1.7 = 1.7 kCal

Grams from Proteins: 0 + 0 + 0.64 = 0.64g

Total Calorie Breakdown Calories: 406.51 kCal

% Carbs: 99.33%

% Fats: 0.25%

% Proteins: 0.41%
 --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 02:27:57 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.tumblingowl.com/stitchwich/recipes/preblog/2014/05/05/Iced-Tea/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tumblingowl.com/stitchwich/recipes/preblog/2014/05/05/Iced-Tea/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
